Records of the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia; Law, Appellate, and Criminal Records; Case Papers 1802-1863
Center for Digital Research in the Humanities University of Nebraska–Lincoln
Records of the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia.; Law, Appellate, and Criminal Records; Case Papers 1802-1863
U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia.
976 boxes 450.19 linear feet
RG0021 Entry 6
Restrictions:
Unknown
Scope and Content:
The records are in boxes with labels that provide the year of the case, a term designated by month, the kind of case, and the associated docket number if available.
Subjects:
U.S. District Court; District of Columbia
Container List:
- Records of the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia; Law, Appellate, and Criminal Records; Case Papers 1802-1863
  - Miscellaneous, U.S. v. Sabrett Scott "For conspiring with Negroes"; 1801-1808, (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Civil Appearances, Ann Shorter v. Thomas Corcoran; 1808, June-Dec. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Civil Appearances, Ann Shorter v. Daniel Rapine; 1808, June-Dec. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Civil Appearances, Ann Shorter v. George Fenwick; 1808, June-Dec. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Civil Appearances, Nelly Brown v. Nicholas Young; 1808, June-Dec. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Civil Appearances, Nelly Brown v. Mary Young; 1808, June-Dec. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Civil Appearances, Becky Joice v. William Jenkins; 1808, June-Dec. (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Civil Appearances, Philis Butler v. Augustin Saira; 1808, June-Dec. (Box 2, Folder 133)
  - Civil Appearances, Henny Joyce v. Thomas Conner; 1808, June-Dec.; Black Washingtonians says "Henry Joyce" as petitioner (Box 2, Folder unnumbered)
  - Civil Appearances, Elizabeth Bentley v. Thomas Keen; 1808, June-Dec. (Box 2, Folder unnumbered)
  - Civil Appearances, Sarah Oakley v. Mary Ann Fenwick; 1808, June-Dec. (Box 2, Folder unnumbered)
  - Civil Appearances, Catherine Killegrew v. Mary Ann Fenwick; 1808, June-Dec. (Box 2, Folder unnumbered)
  - Civil Appearances, William Killegrew v. Daniel Carroll petition for freedom; 1809, June (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Civil Appearances, Susan Joyce v. Daniel Carroll petition for freedom; 1809, June (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Civil Appearances, Joseph Varden v. John Clay; 1809, June; sale of "4 Negroes" for $1500 (Clay was from New Orleans, not Washington; laws regulating the sale of slaves in the District probably complicated this case) (Box 3, Folder 151)
  - Civil Trials, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Petitions, References and Recognizances, Edward H. Calvert v. James C. Lee; 1809, June; Lee promised to pay Calvert $250 and accrued interest for "a Negro Girl named Betty" (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - Civil Trials, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Petitions, References and Recognizances, U.S. v. John Watkins; 1809, June; Watkins "did willingly entertain, and willingly permit and suffer to be about his house, a certain negro woman slave, named Lydia, then and there unlawfully absenting herself from her master and owner..." (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Equity, 1809, June (Box 5)
  - Coroner's Inquests, Judicials, 1-82, Susan Davis and her daughter Airy v. Caleb Swan; 1809, June; judgment in their favor of $37.62 1/2 or 186 lbs. Tobacco "for their costs and charges by them about their suits (in behalf of their freedom prosecuted in the said court) laid out and expended" (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Coroner's Inquests, Judicials, 1-82, 4/8/1809 Henry Butler; 1809, June; "a free Black man... found floating in Rock Creek on the 8th of April with a silver watch in his pocket and a gold ring on his finger... (Box 6, Folder unknown)
  - Coroner's Inquests, Judicials, 1-82, 4/11/1809 Henry Bealls; 1809, June; (includes testimony of George Peck, "a Black man who acted as cook" on frigate U.S.S. United States) (Box 6, Folder unknown)
  - Coroner's Inquests, Judicials, 1-82, 4/29/1809 "John a Black Boy who was accidentally Buried in the Sand Bank"; 1809, June (Box 6, Folder unknown)
  - Coroner's Inquests, Judicials, 1-82, 8/28/1809 "Negro Harry a Slave who was accidentally drowned in the Eastern Branch"; 1809, June (Box 6, Folder unknown)
  - Coroner's Inquests, Judicials, 1-82, S. H. Smallwood v. James Veitch "l Negro Boy named Nicholas" $300; 1809, June (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Judicials, 83-166, 1809, June (Box 7)
  - Civil Appearances, 1-186, James Currill v. Archibald McMullin Petition for freedom (F.S. Key, attorney); 1809, December (Box 8, Folder 174)
  - Civil Appearances, 187-373, Peter Thomas; 1809, December; } "they are entitled to be free, being descended from a free white woman whose name was Elizabeth Thomas, in the female line" (Box 9, Folder 271)
  - Civil Appearances, 187-373, Walter Thomas & Dennis Thomas; 1809, December; } "they are entitled to be free, being descended from a free white woman whose name was Elizabeth Thomas, in the female line" (Box 9, Folder 272)
  - Civil Trials, 10-129, Negro Charles and Nan his wife v. Daniel Mosley et al. (F .S. Key, attorney); 1809, December (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Civil Trials, 132-245, Henrietta, Henry & Stephen v. Gilbert Docker petition for freedom; 1809, December (Box 11, Folder 235)
  - Civil Trials, 132-245, John, Terrissa & Mary Ann Davis v. Hezekiah Wood petition for freedom; 1809, December (Box 11, Folder 236)
  - Civil Trials, 132-245, Negro Ben v. Sabrett Scott petition for freedom (see June term 1811, Civil Trial 190); 1809, December (Box 11, Folder 246)
    no file #246 in box
  - Appeals, Bail Bonds, Criminal Appearances, Imparlances, Rough Bundle, 1809, December (Box 12)
  - Equity, Andrew J. Villard v. John Darby; 1809, December; fraudulent sale of "a negro man slave by the name of James" (Box 13, Folder 75)
  - Equity, Negress Sall v. Thomas Bird et al.; 1809, December; "On behalf of herself and her child James an infant aged one year" (Box 13, Folder 78)
  - Judicials, 1809, December (Box 14)
  - References, 1-65, 1809, December (Box 15)
  - References, 66-129, 1809, December (Box 16)
  - References, 66-129, Alexander Scott v. Elias B. Caldwell; 1809, December; "Hire of negroes Harry, Billy & Basil" (Billy for three months; Harry for one year, Basil for three years: total $258.13) (Box 16, Folder 74)
  - Civil Appearances, 2-131, 1810, June (Box 17)
  - Civil Appearances, 132-339, 1810, June (Box 18)
  - Civil Trials, 15-122, Samuel Speake v. Samuel Davidson; 1810, June; involved a "small negro girl named Mary," valued at $65, and/or "one Negro Girl about 8 years old," valued at $75—perhaps different appraisals of the same person (Box 19, Folder 88)
  - Civil Trials, 15-122, Daniel Carroll v. Henry Whitcroft; 1810, June; involved 5 males, aged 10-45, and 6 females, aged 16-40 (total value $2375), seized for unpaid taxes (Box 19, Folder 105)
  - Civil Trials, 15-122, Arnold Elzey v. Joseph Thompson; 1810, June; arising out of "the hire of a negro man called Isaac" (Elzey's slave) (Box 19, Folder 106)
  - Civil Trials, 124-221, Mima Queen v. John Hepburn; 1810, June; hinges on whether her female ancestor was free or slave (Box 20, Folder 207)
    petition for freedom
  - Civil Trials, 124-221, Alexia Queen v. John Davis petition for freedom; 1810, June (Box 20, Folder 209)
  - Civil Trials, 124-221, Walter & Dennis Thomas v. Alexander Scott; 1810, June; a particularly thick ﬁle (see Civil Appearance 272, December term 1809); petition for freedom (Box 20, Folder 217)
  - Civil Trials, 124-221, Peter Thomas v. Christiana Hamilton; 1810, June; (see Civil Appearance 271, December term 1809); petition for freedom (Box 20, Folder 218)
  - Civil Trials, 124-221, Margaret Joes & children v. Fellow Hewes petition for ﬁeedom; 1810, June (Box 20, Folder 220)
  - Civil Trials, 124-221, Isaac & Edward Davis v. John Travis petition for freedom; 1810, June (Box 20, Folder 221)
  - Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials and Administration Bonds, U.S. v. Richard Spalding; 1810, June; assault and battery ‘upon one Negro Charles the slave of one Thomas B. Bealle" (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials and Administration Bonds, U.S. v. John Cannon; 1810, June; same charge as above (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials and Administration Bonds, U.S. v. Oswald Hughes; 1810, June; assault and battery "on a Negro Man to the jurors... as yet unknown" (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials and Administration Bonds, U.S. v. Thomas Oliver; 1810, June; bigamy (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials and Administration Bonds, U.S. v. Azeriah; 1810, June; "a free negro" stealing goods and money worth $800 (Box 21, Folder 39)
  - Imparlances, Appeals, Recognizances and Coroner's Inquests, Richard Picknall v. John Minitre; 1810, June; "a negro girl named Sal" $120 "a negro boy named basil" 150 "negro Lucy" 125 (Box 22, Folder 139)
  - Imparlances, Appeals, Recognizances and Coroner's Inquests, 1810, June; "Negro Chester... accidentally killed by falling out of the Cart and the wheel striking his head" (Box 22, Folder unnumbered)
  - Imparlances, Appeals, Recognizances and Coroner's Inquests, 1810, June; "Negro Celia who died by the Visitation of God" (Box 22, Folder unnumbered)
  - Imparlances, Appeals, Recognizances and Coroner's Inquests, 1810, June; "a negro Child which died suddenly by the Visitation of God" (Box 22, Folder unnumbered)
  - Judicials, Jeremiah Boothe v. Sarah Washington; 1810, June; "one negro boy named Willy about 14 or 15 years of age" $225.00 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Judicials, David Bates v. Philip Selby; 1810, June; "one negro man name of Peter about 25 years old" $275.00 (Box 23, Folder 54)
  - Judicials, Elisha Gordon v. Henry Knowles; 1810, June; "one negro man name of Jim about 25 years old" $400.00 "one negro lad named [Tim?] about 15 years old" $350.00 (Box 23, Folder 58)
  - Judicials, B. Higgins v. R. & L.H. Johns; 1810, June; "one yellow lad named Jerry" $250.00 "one negro man" $150.00 (Box 23, Folder 87)
  - Civil Appearances, 1-194, Samuel Busey v. James B. Kortright; 1810, December; "one negro woman named Sarah" $100.00 "one negro boy named Frank" 50.00 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Civil Appearances, 200-498, 1810, December (Box 25)
  - Civil Trials, 6-104, William Hay v. Ignatius Newton; 1810, December; has to do with hiring Hay’s slave, "a negro man named Tom," for 3 months and 13 days, for $51.50 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Civil Trials, 6-104, Francis Newman v. Henley Davis; 1810, December; Davis shot Hannah, Newman’s slave. One deponent said "that he has heard the negro woman called Hannah say that if Davis ever touched her again she would be a match for him and would kill him if she could, that she never had been, nor ever would be Whipped by such a poor Son of a Bitch as he was." Another deponent ‘being asked what was the general Character of the defendant Davis—answer that he is generally thought to be a cruel, bloody minded Ill tempered Person and ﬁirther says not." Another deponent "heard negro woman Hannah say that if Davis struck her she would resist him, that she never had been conquered by an overseer—heard Davis say that the Husband of Hannah had attempted his life and shewed him marks of violence on his throat." Another deponent: "Davis said he wanted them [pistols] to defend himself; he had been attacked by Mr Newmans Negroes once or twice and was determined if they again resisted him to kill them." (Box 26, Folder 60)
  - Civil Trials, 106-210, John Pritchard v. John Minitree; 1810, December; Minitree had seized Pritchard’s slave, a, "negro lad named Peter," valued at $275, "against sureties & pledges & so forth" (Box 27, Folder 123)
  - Civil Trials, 212-231, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials and Imparlances, US. v. Benjamin Beall; 1810, December; Beall stole three woolen blankets (worth $4) and a pair of breeches (worth 50 cents) "from negro John Brown the slave of George French." At issue was John Brown’s ability to testify in the case; the defense held that he was not a competent witness. (Box 28, Folder 37)
  - Civil Trials, 212-231, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials and Imparlances, U.S. v. John Harris Harris; 1810, December; a ree Negro, stabbed "Hugh, otherwise known as Uriah, a negro and the slave of one Job Smith" (Box 28, Folder 38)
  - Civil Trials, 212-231, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials and Imparlances, U.S. v. Negro Levi; 1810, December; for stealing 1/4 of a cord of wood (worth one dollar) (Box 28, Folder 45)
  - Civil Trials, 212-231, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials and Imparlances, Mary Lane v. David Bates; 1810, December; "one yellow Girl named Eliza" $250.00 (Box 28, Folder 29)
  - Judicials, 1810, December (Box 29)
  - Appeals, Presentments, Recognizances and Rough Bundle, Petition for Freedom—Rezin Ogleton (sic) v. Isaac Franklin; 1810, December (Box 30, Folder rough bundle)
  - Appeals, Presentments, Recognizances and Rough Bundle, Petitions for Freedom—Resin Overton (sic) and Amy, Daniel, Joan, Nelly, Pompey and Susan Overton, "having lineally descended in the female line from a free woman"; 1810, December (Box 30, Folder rough bundle)
  - Civil Appearances, 1-175, George A. Thomas v. Fielding Parker; 1811, June; "one negro girl named Charity aged about 10 years old" $160.00 (Box 31, Folder 34)
  - Civil Appearances, 177-427, 1811, June (Box 32)
  - Civil Trials, 3-177, 1811, June (Box 33)
  - Civil Trials, 190-201, Criminal Appearances, Recognizances and Rough Bundle, Negro Ben v. Sabrett Scott petition for freedom; 1811, June (Box 34, Folder 190)
  - Civil Trials, 190-201, Criminal Appearances, Recognizances and Rough Bundle, Susan Bordley and her children v. Anne Tilley petition for freedom; 1811, June (Box 34, Folder 191)
  - Civil Trials, 190-201, Criminal Appearances, Recognizances and Rough Bundle, Michael & Anthony Oakley v. Notley Young petition for freedom; 1811, June (Box 34, Folder 193)
  - Civil Trials, 190-201, Criminal Appearances, Recognizances and Rough Bundle, Leticia & Rachel Davis v. Rebecca Forrest petition for freedom; 1811, June; Black Washingtonians says "Loeticia & Rachael" (Box 34, Folder 194)
  - Civil Trials, 190-201, Criminal Appearances, Recognizances and Rough Bundle, Negress Patty et al. v. Thomas & Gerard Greenﬁeld petition for freedom; 1811, June; Black Washingtonians says "Gerrard: (Box 34, Folder 196)
  - Civil Trials, 190-201, Criminal Appearances, Recognizances and Rough Bundle, Ann Davis and her children v. Charles Minifee petition for freedom; 1811, June (Box 34, Folder 197)
  - Civil Trials, 190-201, Criminal Appearances, Recognizances and Rough Bundle, Negro Anne v. Elisha W. Williams petition for freedom; 1811, June (Box 34, Folder 201)
  - Civil Trials, 190-201, Criminal Appearances, Recognizances and Rough Bundle, U.S. v. Richard Bevans; 1811, June; "free mulatto," for assault and battery on Polly Bevans (Bevans appears on that term’s "List of Prisoners Conﬁned in the Jail," but without any racial distinction) (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Civil Trials, 190-201, Criminal Appearances, Recognizances and Rough Bundle, U.S. v. William Smith; 1811, June; "free negro," for keeping a disorderly house ("gaming" was written on the printed form, above the usual words "drinking, tippling, whoring, and misbehaving themselves unlawfully") (Box 34, Folder 38)
  - Civil Trials, 190-201, Criminal Appearances, Recognizances and Rough Bundle, "Inquest on James Smith a yellow Boy who was accidentally drowned in Rock Creek"; 1811, June (Box 34, Folder unnumbered)
  - Imparlances, 1811, June (Box 35)
  - Judicials, 1811, June (Box 36)
  - Civil Appearances, 3-127, 1811, December (Box 37)
  - Civil Trials, 4-120, 1811, December (Box 38)
  - Civil Trials, 123-218, Davy Davis v. James Cassin petition for freedom; 1811, December (Box 39, Folder 214)
  - Civil Trials, 123-218, Sarah Davis v. James Clerklee petition for freedom; 1811, December (Box 39, Folder 215)
  - Civil Trials, 123-218, George Davis v. Mary Young petition for freedom; 1811, December (Box 39, Folder 218)
  - Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Recognizances and Rough Bundle, U.S. v. Susannah Molby; 1811, December; "free mulatto woman," for assault and battery on Ann Flint (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Recognizances and Rough Bundle, US. v. Ling Nickles; 1811, December; "free negro," for stealing one jacket worth $2.50 and a handkerchief worth 50 cents (Box 40, Folder 75)
  - Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Recognizances and Rough Bundle, U.S. v. Thomas Hawkins; 1811, December; "free negro," for assault and battery on Liddy Butler (Box 40, Folder 77)
  - Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Recognizances and Rough Bundle, U.S. v. Jesse Tyler; 1811, December; "free mulatto," for stealing one barrel of herring worth $4, and four pairs of shoes worth $4 (Box 40, Folder 79)
  - Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Recognizances and Rough Bundle, US v. Jim Thomas; 1811, December; "slave," for breaking and entering and stealing 150 pounds of bacon worth $20 (Box 40, Folder 94)
  - Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Recognizances and Rough Bundle, U.S. v. Negro Ninian; 1811, December; Ninian Nicholls, "free negro," stole a shoulder of bacon worth 75 cents (Box 40, Folder rough bundle)
  - Imparlances, 1811, December (Box 41)
  - Judicials, William C. Newton v. George Adams; 1811, December; "one Negro Girl named Sabra" $250.00 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Judicials, John Vint v. Levi White; 1811, December; "one negro man [illegible]" 300.00 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Judicials, Peter Hoffman v. Ann Tilloy; 1811, December; "1 negro girl named Charlotte aged about 15 years" 200.00 (Box 42, Folder 53)
  - Civil Appearances, 1-161, 1812, June (Box 43)
  - Civil Appearances, 163-375, 1812, June (Box 44)
  - Civil Trials, 1-105, Samuel Scott V. Henry Edwards; 1812, June; "hire of a negro woman" L12-1-101/2 ($32.22) (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Civil Trials, 1-105, Jacob Ducket v. Francis Jenkins; 1812, June; "one negro man named Andrew about 33 years old" $300.00 "one negro boy named John about 14 or 15 years old" $300.00 (Box 45, Folder 99)
  - Civil Trials, 107-197, R.H. Picknall v. W. Rider; 1812, June; "1 negro boy named bill aged about 16 years" $250.00 "1 Negro Girl named Sall aged about 12 years" 175.00 (Box 46, Folder 120)
  - Civil Trials, 199-263, Negro Joe v. George Chapman petition for freedom; 1812, June (Box 47, Folder 252)
  - Civil Trials, 199-263, John and Serena v. Henry Moscross petition for freedom; 1812, June (Box 47, Folder 253)
  - Civil Trials, 199-263, Esther Bradley v. Elizabeth Wilson petition for freedom; 1812, June (Box 47, Folder 254)
  - Civil Trials, 199-263, Rachel Lyons and her children v. Richard M. Johnson petition for freedom; 1812, June (Box 47, Folder 257)
  - Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Recognizances and Rough Bundle, Inquest "on a female infant the child of Biddy a Slave of William Rhodes who died Suddenly by the Ill treatment of the Mother"; 1812, June (Box 48, Folder rough bundle)
  - Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Recognizances and Rough Bundle, Inquest "on Negro John the Property of Mrs Hamilton who being in a State of intoxication died by the abuse he gave himself; 1812, June (Box 48, Folder rough bundle)
  - Imparlances, 1812, June (Box 49)
  - Judicials, 1812, June (Box 50, Folder 29)
  - Judicials, Thady Hogan v. William Thornton; 1812, June; "one negro man named John" $350.00 (Box 50, Folder 67)
  - Civil Trials, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials and Rough Bundle, Suman Bishop v. Henry Knowles; 1812, December; "one yellow Girl named Mariah" 280.00 (Box 51)
  - Civil Appearances, 1-162, Sarah Green v. Alexander Spalding; 1813, June; petition for freedom; Not on Black Washingtonians (Box 52, Folder 59)
  - Civil Appearances, 167-371, 1813, June (Box 53)
  - Civil Trials, 4-218, 1813, June (Box 54)
  - Civil Trials, 220-261, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Appeals and Rough Bundle, Priscilla Queen v. Francis Neale petition for freedom; 1813, June (Box 55, Folder 249)
  - Civil Trials, 220-261, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Appeals and Rough Bundle, Hester Queen v. J. Nevitt & R. Nally petition for freedom; 1813, June (Box 55, Folder 250)
  - Civil Trials, 220-261, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Appeals and Rough Bundle, Matilda Gray and her child v. Mary Ann Pic petition for freedom; 1813, June (Box 55, Folder 255)
  - Civil Trials, 220-261, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Appeals and Rough Bundle, Thomas J. Browner v. Horatio Smallwood; 1813, June; "hire negro girl" $15.00 (Box 55, Folder 257)
  - Civil Trials, 220-261, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Appeals and Rough Bundle, U.S. v. Joseph Butler; 1813, June; Butler, a carpenter and "free negroe," was charged with stealing "one sorrel bay gelding" worth $120 (Box 55, Folder 47)
  - Civil Trials, 220-261, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Appeals and Rough Bundle, U.S. v. Joseph Butler; 1813, June; Same defendant charged with stealing one saddle ($5), one bridle ($5) and "one great coat of woolen cloth" ($7) (Box 55, Folder 48)
  - Civil Trials, 220-261, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Appeals and Rough Bundle, Coroner’s inquest on "a Negro Lad named Bill...drowned in the Waters of Rock Creek..."; 1813, June (Box 55, Folder rough bundle)
  - Imparlances and Recognizances, Judicials, 1-35, 1813, June (Box 56)
  - Judicials, 37-185, Mary Shaw v. Henry Knowles; 1813, June; "one negro man named Levi" $350.00 (Box 57, Folder 54)
  - Judicials, 37-185, William Stewart v. Henry Knowles; 1813, June; "one negro man named Levi" $350.00 (Levi’s state of mind, as the stake in simultaneous lawsuits, may be imagined.) (Box 57)
  - Civil Appearances, 4-154, Negro Rachel and child v. James Torrance Petition for freedom; 1813, December; Black Washingtonians said "Jonathan Morris" as defendant (Box 58, Folder 56)
  - Civil Appearances, 156-375, Lewis H. Machen v. Thomas Dunn; 1813, December; "one Negro boy About ten years old named George" $200.00 "one Negro girl named Mariah about eight years old" $150.00 (Box 59, Folder 224)
  - Civil Appearances, 156-375, John G. McDonald Vv Thomas Dunn; 1813, December; "One Negro boy named William about 4 years old" $100.00 (Box 59, Folder 228)
  - Civil Trials, 6-114, 1813, December (Box 60)
  - Civil Trials, 116-197, 1813, December (Box 61)
  - Civil Trials, 199-293, 1813, December (Box 62)
  - Appeals, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Imparlances, Recognizances and Rough Bundle, 1813, December (Box 63)
  - Appeals, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Imparlances, Recognizances and Rough Bundle, U.S. v. Harry Thompson; 1813, December; "free negroe" stealing 7 calfskins worth $27.00 (Box 63, Folder 42)
  - Appeals, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Imparlances, Recognizances and Rough Bundle, U.S. v. Azariah Kitts; 1813, December; "free negroe" stole clothing and bed linen worth $18.00 (Box 63, Folder 46)
  - Appeals, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Imparlances, Recognizances and Rough Bundle, U.S. v. Polly Brown; 1813, December; "free negress" stole one calico gown worth $3.00 (Box 63, Folder 47)
  - Appeals, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Imparlances, Recognizances and Rough Bundle, U.S. v. Polly Brown; 1813, December; stole dresses, shoes and bonnet worth $24.00 (Box 63, Folder 48)
  - Judicials, 1-72, U.S. v. Nancy Swann; 1813, December; "free mulatto" stole one silk umbrella worth $4.00 (Box 64, Folder 49)
  - Judicials, 74-141, Thomas Williams v. Samuel Speake; 1813, December; "one negro girl or woman named Eliza about 16 years old" $200.00 (Box 65, Folder 23)
  - Civil Appearances, 2-169, 1814, June (Box 66)
  - Civil Appearances, 173-385, 1814, June (Box 67)
  - Civil Trials, 10-126, Samuel S. Hamilton v. Spence Grayson; 1814, June; "One Negro man named Jesse to serve" 2 years, 9 months $125.00 (Box 68, Folder 46)